<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="LongerNow.rng" type="xml"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="LongerNow.css" title="Original"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title n="1">The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death</title>
					<title n="2">"oxenofthesun"</title>
				<respStmt>
					<resp></resp>
					<name></name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher> "The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death" published by David Carlton as part of the "Long Now of Ulysses" library exhibit, hosted, sponsored and produced by the University of Victoria, English 507 and English 520.</publisher>
				<sponsor> UVic </sponsor>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<author>
						<name>James Joyce</name>
					</author>
					<title>Ulysses</title>
					<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
					<publisher>Shakespeare and Company</publisher>
					<date>1922</date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text vowels="493" consonants="802" xml:space="preserve">
		<body>
			<head type="main"></head>
			<lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="1">				
				<l type="narration">   him  for that  time in the honourablest manner.  Ruth red him,  love led on with</l>
				<l type="narration">   will  to  wander,  loth  to  leave.</l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontsize="normal"><p n="2">
				<lb><l type="narration">For they were right  witty scholars.  And he  heard their  aresouns  each  gen</l></lb>
				<l type="narration">   other as touching birth and righteousness,  young  Madden maintaining that put</l>
				<l type="narration">   such  case  it were hard the wife to die  (for so it  had fallen out a matter of some</l>
				<l type="narration">   year agone with a woman of  Eblana  in  Horne's house  that now was trespassed</l>
				<l type="narration">   out  of  this  world   and  the  self  night  next  before  her death  all  leeches  and</l>
				<l type="narration">   pothecaries  had  taken  counsel  of  her  case).  And they said farther she  should</l>
				<l type="narration">   live because in the  beginning  they  said  the woman should  bring  forth in  pain</l>
				<l type="narration">   and wherefore they that were of  this  imagination  affirmed how young  Madden</l>
				<l type="narration">   had said truth for  he  had  conscience to let her die.  And  not  few and  of  these</l>
				<l type="narration">   was young  Lynch  were in doubt that the world  was now right evil  governed  as</l>
				<l type="narration">   it was never other  howbeit  the  mean  people  believed it  otherwise  but the law</l>
				<l type="narration">   nor his judges did  provide no remedy  A redress God grant.  This was  scant  said</l>
				<l type="narration">   but all cried with one acclaim nay,  by  our  Virgin  Mother,  the wife  should  live</l>
   				<l type="narration">   and the babe to die. In colour whereof they waxed hot upon that head  what  with</l>
  			    <l type="narration">   argument and what for their drinking but the franklin Lenehan was prompt  each</l>
				<l type="narration">   when to  pour  them  ale so  that  at  the  least  way  mirth  might  not  lack.  Then</l>
				<l type="narration">   young  Madden  showed  all the whole affair and  when he said how  that  she was</l>
				<l type="narration">   dead  and  how for holy  religion sake  by  rede of palmer and bedesman and  for a</l>
				<l type="narration">   vow he had made to  Saint Ultan of Arbraccan her  goodman husband  would  not</l>
				<l type="narration">   let her death whereby  they were all wondrous grieved.  To whom  young  Stephen</l></p>

</lg>
				
</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
