<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="LongerNow.rng" type="xml"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="LongerNow.css" title="Original"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title n="1">The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death</title>
				<title n="2">"cyclops"</title>
				<respStmt>
					<resp></resp>
					<name></name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher> "The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death" published by David Carlton as part of the "Long Now of Ulysses" library exhibit, hosted, sponsored and produced by the University of Victoria, English 507 and English 520.</publisher>
				<sponsor> UVic </sponsor>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<author>
						<name>James Joyce</name>
					</author>
					<title>Ulysses</title>
					<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
					<publisher>Shakespeare and Company</publisher>
					<date>1922</date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text vowels="404" consonants="665" xml:space="preserve">
		<body>
			<head type="main"></head>
			<lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="1">				
				<l type="narration">   reposed a savage animal of the  canine tribe  whose  stertorous  gasps  announced</l>
				<l type="narration">   that he was such in  uneasy slumber,  a supposition  confirmed  by  hoarse  growls</l>
				<l type="narration">   and spasmodic movements  which  his  master  repressed  from  time to  time  by</l>
				<l type="narration">   tranquilising blows of a mighty cudgel rudely fashioned out  of  paleolithic  stone.</l></p></lg><lg type = "speech" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="2">
				<lb><l type="narration">So anyhow Terry brought the three pints  Joe  was  standing  and  begob  the</l></lb>
				<l type="narration">   sight nearly left  my eyes when  I  saw him  land  out  a  quid.  O,  as  true as  I'm</l>
				<l type="narration">   telling you.  A goodlooking sovereign.</l>
				<lb><l type="speech">—  <q>And there's more where that came from</q>,  says he.</l></lb>
				<lb><l type="speech">—  <q>Were you robbing the poorbox,  Joe ? say I ?</q> </l></lb>
				<lb><l type="speech">—  <q>Sweat of my brow</q>,  says  Joe.  <q>'Twas  the  prudent  member  gave   me  the</q></l></lb>
				<l type="speech">   <q>wheeze.</q></l>
				<lb><l type="speech">—  <q>I  saw  him  before I  met you</q>,  says  I,  <q>sloping  around  by  Pill  lane  and</q></l></lb>
				<l type="speech">    <q>Greek  street  with  a  cod's eye  counting  up  all  the guts of the fish.</q></l>
				<lb><l type="speech"><q>Who comes through Michan's land,  bedight in sable armour?  O'Bloom, the</q></l></lb>
				<l type="speech">    <q>son of Rory : it  is  he.  Impervious  to fear is Rory's son : he  of the  prudent soul</q></l>
   				<lb><l type="speech">—  <q>For the old  woman  of  Prince's  street</q>,  says  the  citizen,  <q>the  subsidised</q></l></lb>
  			    <l type="speech">    <q>organ.  The  pledgebound  party  on  the  floor  of  the  house.  And  look  at  this</q></l>
				<l type="speech">    <q>blasted rag</q>,  says  he.  <q>Look at this</q>,  says  he.  <q><w type="italic">The Irish Independent</w>, if  you  please</q>,</l>
				<l type="speech">    <q>founded  by Parnell  to  be  the  workingman's  friend.  Listen  to  the  births and</q></l>
				<l type="speech">    <q>deaths   in  the  <w type="italic">Irish   all  for   Ireland   Independent</w>  and   I'll  thank   you   and  the</q></l>
				<l type="speech">    <q>marriages.</q></l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="3">
				<lb><l type="narration">And  he starts  reading them out :</l></lb></p>

</lg>
				
</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
