<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="LongerNow.rng" type="xml"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="LongerNow.css" title="Original"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title n="1">The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death</title>
				<title n="2">"eumaeus"</title>
				<respStmt>
					<resp></resp>
					<name></name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher> "The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death" published by David Carlton as part of the "Long Now of Ulysses" library exhibit, hosted, sponsored and produced by the University of Victoria, English 507 and English 520.</publisher>
				<sponsor> UVic </sponsor>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<author>
						<name>James Joyce</name>
					</author>
					<title>Ulysses</title>
					<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
					<publisher>Shakespeare and Company</publisher>
					<date>1922</date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text vowels="497" consonants="807" xml:space="preserve">
		<body>
			<head type="main"></head>
			<lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="1">				
				<l type="narration">   Boodle  they  could  in  one  fell  swoop  at  a  moment's notice,  your  money  or</l>
				<l type="narration">   your life,   leaving  you  there to point a moral,  gagged and garrotted.</l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="2">	
				<lb><l type="narration">Stephen, that is when the  accosting  figure came  to  close  quarters,  though</l></lb>
				<l type="narration">   he was not in any over  sober  state himself,  recognised  Corley's breath  redolent</l>
				<l type="narration">   of rotten cornjuice.  Lord John Corley,  some called him, and his genealogy came</l>
				<l type="narration">   about in this wise. He was the eldest some of Inspector Corley of the G Division</l>
				<l type="narration">   lately deceased,  who had married  a  certain Katherine Brophy,  the  daughter of</l>
				<l type="narration">   a Louth  farmer.  His  grandfather,  Patrick Michael Corley,  of  New  Ross,  had</l>
				<l type="narration">   married  the widow of a publican there whose maiden name had been  Katherine</l>
				<l type="narration">   (also)  Talbot.  Rumour  had  it,  though  not  proved,  that  she  descended  from</l>
				<l type="narration">   the   house  of  the  Lords  Talbot  de  Malahide,  in  whose  mansion,   really  an</l>
				<l type="narration">   unquestionably fine residence of its kind and well  worth  seeing,   her  mother or</l>
				<l type="narration">   aunt  or  some  relative  had  enjoyed  the  distinction of  being in  service in  the</l>
				<l type="narration">   washkitchen.   This,  therefore,  was the reason why  he still comparatively  young</l>
				<l type="narration">   though  dissolute  man  who  now  addressed  Stephen  was  spoken  of  by  some</l>
   				<l type="narration">   with facetious  proclivities  as  Lord  John  Corley.</l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="3">	
  			    <lb><l type="narration">Taking Stephen on  on  side  he   had   the   customary   doleful  ditty  to  tell.</l></lb>
				<l type="narration">   Not as  much as a  farthing to purchase  a  night's  lodgings.  His  friends  had  all</l>
				<l type="narration">   deserted  him.   Furthermore,  he  had  a  row  with  Leneban  and  called  him  to</l>
				<l type="narration">   Stephen a mean bloody swab  with a  sprinkling of  other uncalledfor  expressions.</l>
				<l type="narration">   He was out  of  a job and implored of  Stephen to tell him where on  God's  earth</l>
				<l type="narration">   he could  get  something,  anything at all to do.  No,  it was  the  daughter  of  the</l></p>

</lg>
				
</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
