<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="LongerNow.rng" type="xml"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="LongerNow.css" title="Original"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title n="1">The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death</title>
				<title n="2">"calypso"</title>
				<respStmt>
					<resp></resp>
					<name></name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher> "The Longer Now of Ulysses: Digital Life After Analog Death" published by David Carlton as part of the "Long Now of Ulysses" library exhibit, hosted, sponsored and produced by the University of Victoria, English 507 and English 520.</publisher>
				<sponsor> UVic </sponsor>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<author>
						<name>James Joyce</name>
					</author>
					<title>Ulysses</title>
					<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
					<publisher>Shakespeare and Company</publisher>
					<date>1922</date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text vowels="454" consonants="716" xml:space="preserve">
		<body>
			<head type="main"></head>
			<lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="1">				
				<l type="narration">Olives  cheaper  :  oranges  need  artificial  irrigation.   Every  year   you   get  a</l>
				<l type="narration">sending of  the  crop.  Your name entered  for  life  as owner  in the book of the</l>
				<l type="narration">union.   Can pay ten down and  the  balance  in  yearly  instalments.  Bleibtreu-</l>
				<l type="narration">strasse 34, Berlin, W, 15.</l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="2">	
				<lb><l type="narration">Nothing doing. Still an idea behind it.</l></lb></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="3">	
				<lb><l type="narration">He looked at the cattle, blurred  in silver  heat.  Silvered  powdered  olive-</l></lb>
				<l type="narration">trees. Quiet long days: pruning ripening. Olives are packed in jars, eh? I  have a</l>
				<l type="narration">few left from Andrews. Molly spitting them out.  Knows the tase of them  now.</l>
				<l type="narration">Oranges in  tissue paper packed in crates.  Citrons too.  Wonder is  poor Citron</l>
				<l type="narration">still alive in Saint Kevin's parade. And Mastiansky with the old  cither. Pleasant</l>
				<l type="narration">evenings we had then.  Molly in Citron's basketchair.  Nice to hold, cool waxen</l>
				<l type="narration">fruit,  hold  in  the  hand,  lift it  to  the  nostrils  and  smell  the perfume.  Like</l>
				<l type="narration">that,  heavy,  sweet,  wild perfume.   Always  the  same,   year  after  year.   They</l>
				<l type="narration">fetched high prices too Moisel told me. Arbutus place: Pleasants street: pleasant </l>
				<l type="narration">old times.   Must  be  without a  flaw,  he  said.   Coming  all  that  way :  Spain,</l>
   				<l type="narration">Gibraltar, Mediterranean,  the Levant.  Crates lines up on the quayside at  Jaffa,</l>
  			    <l type="narration">chap ticking them off  in a book,  navvies  handling  them  in  soiled  dungarees.</l>
				<l type="narration">There's whatdoyoucallhim out of.   How do you ?  Doesn't see.  Chap you know</l>
				<l type="narration">just to salute bit of a bore.   His back is  like the  Norwegian  captain's.  Wonder</l>
				<l type="narration">if I'll meet him today.   Watering cart.   To provoke the rain.   On earth  as  it  is </l>
				<l type="narration">in heaven.</l></p></lg><lg type = "paragraph" fontStyle="normal" fontSize="normal"><p n="4">	
				<lb><l type="narration">A cloud began to cover the sun wholly.  Grey.  Far.</l></lb></p>

</lg>
				
</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
